A Finding Aid to the National Arts Club Records, 1898-1960, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Mar., 1922 Lithographs
Apr. 5-30 +, 1922 Loan Exhibition of American Painting and Sculpture Owned by Club Members
May-Oct. +, 1922 Summer Exhibition of Artist Members
Nov., 1922 Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec. 6-29 +, 1922 Work by Members
Jan. 10-Feb. 10 +, 1923 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Feb. 14-Mar. 3 +, 1923 Humorists Exhibition
Mar., 1923 Craftwork from Berea College, Kentucky
Mar., 1923 Group Exhibition: Roy Brown, Oscar Fehrer, Edmund Greacen, Eugene Higgins, Lee Laurie, F. Luis Mora, Carl Rungius, Edward C. Volkert.
Mar. 28-Apr. 20 +, 1923 Group Exhibition: Leon Dabo, William R. Derrick, Charles P. Gruppe, Hayley Lever, Charles R. Patterson
Apr., 1923 Miniature Garden Exhibition, by the Garden Club of America
May-July, 1923 Exhibition Selected from the Permanent Collection
June 5-28 +, 1923 Annual Prize Exhibition of Painter and Sculptor Members
Nov., 1923 Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec. 12-29 +, 1923 Work of Living American Etchers
Jan. 9-Feb. 2 +, 1924 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Mar. 5-29 +, 1924 Exhibition of Sculpture
Apr., 1924 Selected Paintings from the Permanent Collection
Apr. 30-May 15 +, 1924 Exhibition of Books Illustrating the History of Printing
June, 1924 Adirondack Mountain Club Exhibition of Photographs
Nov. *, 1924 Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec. 10-27 +, 1924 Second Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers
Jan. 7-31 +, 1925 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture (N552:122-159)
Feb. 23-Mar. 7 +, 1925 Autograph Letters with Accompanying Portraits of Authors, Statesmen, Artists, etc.
Apr. 8-May 9 +, 1925 Exhibition of Lithographs, Wood Blocks, and Linoleum Cuts
Nov., 1925 Twentieth Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec. 3-20, 1925 Work of Living American Etchers (N552:1-7)
Jan. 13-Feb. 6 +, 1926 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture (N552:19-21)
Feb. 10-27 +, 1926 Group Exhibiton by Members of the National Arts Club
Mar. 3-27 +, 1926 Copies of Old Masters
Apr., 1926 Architecture, Sculpture, and Decorative Painting
May +, 1926 Fifth International Exhibition of the Brooklyn Society of Etchers (N552:34-48)
Summer +, 1926 Summer Exhibition
Aug.-Oct. x, 1926 The Vollbehr Incunabula Exhibition
Nov., 1926 Twenty-first Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec. 2-22 +, 1926 Fourth Annual Exhibition of Works of Living American Etchers (N552:8-12)
Jan. 5-29 +, 1927 Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Members
Feb. 11-27 +, 1927 Exhibition and Auction of Works of Art by Artist Members
Mar. 2-21 +, 1927 Invited Exhibition by Distinguished American Painters (NHS4:693-695)
Apr. 6-29 +, 1927 Norse Pictorial Weaving--Mrs. Berthea Aske Bergh (N552:66-68)
Nov., 1927 Twenty-second Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec. 7-24 +, 1927 Fifth Annual Exhibition of Works of Living American Etchers (N552:13-18)
Jan., 1928 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Feb. 8-29 +, 1928 Small Paintings
Mar. 8-31 x, 1928 Exhibition of Decorative Arts
Apr. 4-20 +, 1928 Exhibition by Junior Artist Members of the Club
Nov., 1928 Twenty-third Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec., 1928 Small Paintings
Jan. 8-Feb. 8 + Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Feb. 13-Mar. 8 Sixth Annual Exhibition by Living American Etchers
Mar. + Richard M. Hurd Loan Exhibition of Italian Primitives
Apr. 3-26 + Exhibition by Junior Artist Members of the Club
May 1-Oct. 1 + Summer Exhibition by Painter Life Members
Nov. Twenty-fourth Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec. 4-26 * + Exhibition of the Decorative Arts
Jan. 8-Feb. 1 +, 1930 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Feb. 5-28 x +, 1930 Seventh Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers
Mar. 5-28 +, 1930 Junior Artist Members' Exhibition
Apr. 16-Sept. 30 +, 1930 Members' Exhibition of Small Paintings (N134:484-490)
Nov., 1930 Silver Anniversary Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec. 3-26 * +, 1930 Eighth Annual Exhibition by Living American Etchers
Jan. 7-Feb. 6 +, 1931 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Mar. 4-27 +, 1931 Exhibition by the Junior Artist Members
Mar. 13-Apr. 15 x, 1931 Auction Exhibition and Sale by Artist Members
Apr. 1-25 +, 1931 Members' Work of the New York Water Color Club
May 2-24 +, 1931 The Story of Gramercy Park in Portraits and Historical Objects of the Period, in connection with Gramercy Park Centenary Celebration
June 3-Oct. 1 +, 1931 Members' Exhibition of Small Paintings
Oct. 21-Nov. 20, 1931 Twenty-sixth Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Nov. 26-Dec. 26, 1931 Sixteenth Annual Exhibition by the Society of American Etchers (formerly The Brooklyn Society of Etchers)
Jan. 6-13 +, 1932 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Feb. 3-27 +, 1932 Exhibition of Drawings by Artist Members
Mar. 2-26 +, 1932 Paintings by Junior Artist Members
Mar. 13-Apr. 15 +, 1932 Auction Exhibition and Sale by Artist Members
Apr. 20-30 +, 1932 Exhibition by a Group of New York Art Schools
May 4-Oct. 1 +, 1932 Members' Annual Exhibition of Small Paintings
Jan. 4-27 +, 1933 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Mar. 1-31 +, 1933 Junior Artist Members
Apr. 5-22 +, 1933 Society of Illustrators
May 3-Oct. 1 +, 1933 Members' Exhibition of Small Paintings and Sculpture
Jan. 3-27 +, 1934 Members' Annual Exhibition
Jan. 31-Mar. 2 +, 1934 Memorial Exhibition of a Group of Former Painter and Sculptor Members: Max Bohm, Emil Carlsen, Charles Hawthorne, Robert Henri, Karl Bitter, Solon Borglum, Daniel Chester French, Edmund Quinn
Mar. 7-29 +, 1934 Junior Artist Members
Apr. 4-27 +, 1934 Society of Illustrators, Thirty-second Annual Exhibition
May 2-June 28 +, 1934 Members' Exhibition of Small Paintings and Sculpture (N552:69-71; N134:491-494)
Nov.-Dec., 1934 Seventeenth Annual Exhibition of the Society of American Etchers (formerly The Brooklyn Society of Etchers) (N552:49-65)
undated Twenty-ninth Annual Exhibition of Fifty Books of the Year
Jan. 9-Feb. 1 +, 1935 Members' Exhibition (N552:22-24)
Feb. 6-Mar. 2 +, 1935 Members' No Jury Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture (N552:72-74)
Mar. 6-29 +, 1935 Junior Artist Members (N552:75-77)
Apr. 3-27 +, 1935 Loan Exhibition of Works of Art owned by Artist Members (N552:84-96)
undated Thirtieth Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
undated Twentieth Annual Exhibition of the Society of American Etchers
Jan. 8-31 +, 1936 Members' Annual Exhibition (M552:25-27)
Mar. 4-27 +, 1936 Junior Artist Members (N552:78-80)
Apr. 1-May 1 x +, 1936 Exhibition of Neighboring Art Organizations (N552:92-94)
Spring +, 1936 First Annual Exhibition of Pictorial Photography by the Pictorial Forum (N552:87-91)
1936 Thirty-first Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
undated Twenty-first Annual Exhibition of the Society of American Etchers
Jan. 6-29 +, 1937 Members' Annual Exhibition
Mar. 3-26 +, 1937 Exhibition by the Younger Artists Group (N134:495-497)
Mar. 31-Apr. 27 +, 1937 Second Exhibition of Neighboring Art Organizations (N552:95-97)
Nov. *, 1937 Thirty-second Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year
Dec. 8-25 +, 1937 Members' Exhibition of Smaller Paintings and Black and Whites (N552:110-112)
Jan. 12-27, 1938 Exhibition of Former Painter and Sculptor Members (N552:113-115)
Mar. 14-Apr. 2 +, 1938 Third Exhibition of Neighboring Art Organizations (N552:98-100)
Apr. 6-20 +, 1938 Younger Artists Group Exhibition (N552:107-109)
Jan. 12-27 x +, 1939 Memorial Exhibition of the Work of a Group of Former Painter and Sculptor Members (N134:498-499)
Feb. 1-25 +, 1939 Members' Exhibition (N552:28-30)
Mar. 1-31 +, 1939 Exhibition of Flower Paintings (N552:116-118; N134:500-502)
Mar. 3-26, 1939 Younger Artists Group (N552:104-106)
Apr. 5-21 +, 1939 Fourth Annual Exhibition of Neighboring Art Organizations (N552:101-103)
May 10-24 +, 1939 Annual Junior Members' Exhibition (N552:81-83; N134:503-505)
June-Oct. +, 1939 Selected Works by Deceased Artists from the National Arts Club Permanent Collection (N552:119-121; N134:506-508)
Oct. 18-28 +, 1939 Special Exhibition of Paintings by Junior Members
Dec. 4-25 +, 1939 Christmas Sale of Paintings, Drawings, Photographs, and Sculpture by Junior Members
Jan. 3-19 +, 1940 Members' Annual Exhibition
Jan. 24-Feb. 9 +, 1940 Distinguished Exhibition of the Work of Living American Painters, Non-Members
Feb. 14-29 +, 1940 Exhibition and Sale of Ceramics (N134:511-513)
Mar. 19-29, 1940 Fontainebleau Alumni Exhibition
Apr. 3-19 +, 1940 Annual Junior Members' Exhibition
Apr. 24-May 3 +, 1940 Flower and Still Life Paintings
May 8-June 1, 1940 Special Exhibition of Water Colors, Architectural Renderings, Type Compositions, and Color Reproductions by Edwin Hooper Denby, A.I.A., S.A.D.G. (N443:779-780; N134:509-510)
Dec. +, 1940 Twenty-fifth Annual Exhibition of the Society of American Etchers
Feb. 4-Mar. 1, 1942 Exhibition of Paintings by Artists of the United Nations (N134:512-518)
June 12-Sept. 30, 1942 Members' Summer Exhibition (N134:519)
Dec. 16-Jan. 22, 1942 Exhibition of Chinese and Indian Art (N134:520)
Mar. 31-, 1943 Exhibition of Junior Members (N134:521)
July 1-Sept. 30, 1943 Summer Exhibition of Smaller Paintings by Members (N134:522)
Feb. 17-Mar. 15, 1944 Exhibition of Studies by American Masters (N134:523)
Oct. 5-27, 1944 Exhibition of Enlarged Photographs of American Patriots as Seen in Sculpture (N134:523)
Jan. 10-Feb. 9 x, 1945 Members' Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Dec. 22-Jan. 4, 1945 Seventh Annual Exhibition of the American Veterans Society of Artists, Inc. (N134:527-540)
May 21-30, 1946 The Traphagen School Exhibition of Costume Design, Illustrating the Development of American Fashion (N134:526)
Feb. 20-Mar. 7, 1947 Exhibition of Contemporary Chinese Paintings (N134:541)
Apr. 20-May 2, 1947 Junior Members' Exhibition
Dec. 10-24, 1947 Ninth Annual Exhibition of American Veterans Society of Artists, Inc. (N121:721-733)
Feb. 23-Mar. 6, 1948 Forty-seventh Annual Exhibition of the New York Society of Ceramic Arts (N134:543)
Mar. 9-21, 1948 Annual Exhibition of Junior Members (N134:543)
Apr. 8-May 30, 1948 Fiftieth Anniversary Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Members, Past and Present (N134:543)
June 10-Sept., 1948 Members' Summer Exhibition (N134:544)
Jan. 19-Feb. 9, 1949 Fifty-first Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Members and Guest Artists (N134:544)
Mar. 14-31, 1949 Exhibition by Members of the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors (N134:545)
May 5-Sept. 15, 1949 Members' Summer Exhibition (N134:546)
Oct. 15-Nov. 4, 1949 Fourth Annual Exhibition of the Photo-Engravers Society
Jan. 4-Feb. 1, 1950 Fifty-second Annual Exhibition of Paintings and Sculpture by Members and Guest Artists (N134:546-548 and 550)
Jan. 28-Feb. 19, 1950 Eighty-third Annual Exhibition of the American Water Color Society (N134:549)
Feb. 8-23, 1950 Exhibition of Creative Art Associates (N134:549)
Mar. 16-Apr. 2, 1950 Exhibition of Room Interiors Especially Designed by Members of the American Institute of Decorators, in collaboration with Members of the National Society of Mural Painters (N134:551)
May 7-28, 1950 Active Members' Exhibition (N134:551-554)
June 28-Sept. 15, 1950 Members' Summer Exhibition (N134:555)
Feb. 26-Mar. 17 x, 1951 Paul Mommen
Mar. 24-Apr. 19, 1951 Exhibition of Paintings by Non-Members (N134:558-559)
May 5-31, 1951 Spring Water Color Exhibition (N134:560)
June 6-, 1951 Group Exhibition by Distinguished Artist Members: Gifford Beal, Louis Betts, Charles Clapman, Walter Farndon, Albert Groll, Eugene Higgins, Leon Kroll, Van Dearing Perrine, Keith Shaw Williams
Jan. 6-30, 1952 Fifty-fourth Annual Exhibition of Paintings and Sculpture by Members and Guest Artists (D176:917-919; N134:561)
Feb. 9-28, 1952 Annual Water Color Exhibition (N134:562)
Mar. 9-27, 1952 Exhibition of Oil Paintings by Distinguished American Artists (N134:572)
Jan. 4-18, 1953 Fifty-fifth Annual Exhibition by Painter and Sculptor Members and Guest Artists (N134:563)
Jan. 25-Feb. 8, 1953 Annual Water Color Exhibition (N134:564)
Feb. 15-Mar. 1, 1953 Open Exhibition of Oil Paintings (N134:565-568)
Mar. *, 1953 Art of Indonesia
May 3-24, 1953 Members' Exhibition of Smaller Paintings in Oil (N134:569-571)
Nov. 1-14, 1954 The American Artists Professional League, American Art Week (N121:258-259)
Oct. 2-19, 1955 Open Water Color Exhibition
Jan. 8-22 x, 1956 Fifty-eighth Annual Exhibition by Painter and Sculptor Members and Guest Artists (N134:573-575)
June 17-Sept. 7 x, 1956 Members' Summer Exhibition
Sept. 24-Oct. 8 x, 1956 James H. Walsh
Oct. 28-Nov. 10 x, 1956 Small Picture Exhibition by Members and Guests
Nov. 16-30 x, 1956 August Benziger
Dec. 5-22 *, 1956 Fiftieth Anniversary Exhibition of Books of the Year
Jan. 6-27, 1957 Fifty-ninth Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Members and Guest Artists
Feb. 1-15, 1957 Catherine Lorillard Wolfe Art Club Sixtieth Annual Exhibition (N134:576-577)
Sept. * x, 1957 International Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture
Jan. 10-24 x, 1958 Sixtieth Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Members and Guest Artists
May 21-31 x, 1958 Water Color and Graphic Arts Exhibition by Members and Non-Members
Oct. 17-31 x, 1958 Twelfth Annual Exhibition of the Photo-Engravers Society
Nov. 22-Dec. 3 x, 1958 Metropolitan Young Artists Show
Jan. 11-26 x, 1959 Sixty-first Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Members and Guest Artists
Dec. 9-Jan. 7 x, 1959 Metropolitan Young Artists Show
Jan. 15-28 x, 1960 Sixty-second Annual Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Members and Guest Artists
Apr. 18-May 1, 1960 Catherine Lorillard Wolfe Art Club Flower Painting Exhibition and Sale (D176:1128-1129)
June 8-29 x, 1960 Summer Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture by Members
undated * Arts and Crafts Exhibitions
undated * x Annual Exhibitions of Books of the Year
undated * Ceramic Art Exhibition
undated x Water-Oils by Charles S. Chapman, N.A.
undated x Fine Art of the Caribbean
undated x Painters of the United States, 1720-1920, from the Permanent Collection of the Fine Arts Department, International Business Machines Corp.
undated * Pottery Exhibition
undated * Traveling Exhibition of Enlarged Photographs of Sculpture and Spring Exhibition of Small Sculpture by Members of the National Sculpture Society
undated * Exhibition of Small Sculpture
undated x Modern Tapestries from Vienna
undated x Annual Open Water Color Exhibition
undated x Catherine Lorillard Wolfe Art Club, Flower Paintings Exhibition and Sale
undated * Unidentified exhibition installations
Photography -- Exhibitions; Scrapbooks; Bibliographical exhibitions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clubhouses -- New York (State) -- New York; Arts organizations; Arts organizations -- Taxation; Handicraft; Decorative arts; Arts Realty; De Kay, Charles
- Board of Governors, 1898-1960, undated; Series 1; Archival Resource Key
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains minutes and reports of the Board of Governors and Executive Committee from 1898 to 1957, and minutes and reports of various standing and special committees from 1901 to 1939. Board of Governors and Executive Committee minutes and reports are fairly complete through 1949, but sparse thereafter, and include transcriptions of very early correspondence relating to the selection and acquisition of the first clubhouse. Records for special committees are not complete either, and tend to be concentrated in the early twentieth century.
  See Appendix B for a list of officers of the National Arts Club
  Arrangement note
  The series is arranged by committee and then chronologically.
  Appendix B: List of Officers of the National Arts Club, 1899-1960
  President
  1899-1905: George B. Post
  1905-1909: Spencer Trask
  1910-1932: John G. Agar (Honorary President, 1932-1934)
  1932-1937: John Robert Gregg
  1937-1938: John Clyde Oswald
  1938-1942: J. Frederick Talcott
  1942-1947: John Robert Gregg
  1948-1951: Harvey Wiley Corbett
  1951-1954: Bailey B. Burritt
  1954-1957: Lyon McCandless
  1957-1958: Robert K. Chandler
  1958-1959: Boylen Fitzgerald
  1959-1967: Perry J. Walsh
  Treasurer
  1899-1905: Spencer Trask
  1905-circa 1907: James Edward Sague
  circa 1907-circa 1908: Robert H. Rucker
  circa 1910-1913: Richard Welling
  1914-1916: Edward D. Page
  1917: Miles M. Dawson
  1918: Alexander Konta
  1919-1929: John Robert Gregg
  1930-1933: Charles K. Carpenter
  1934-c.1942: Rodney Wilcox Jones
  circa 1953-?: Janet Howell
  circa 1958-1959: Archibald E. Livingston
  Secretary
  1899-1904: Charles de Kay
  1904: Frank Jewett Mather, Jr.
  circa 1905: Henry M. Stegman
  circa 1906-1907: Charles H. Babcock
  circa 1907-circa 1908: Robert Van Iderstine
  1909: R. H. Rucker
  circa 1909-1918: Frederick S. Lamb
  1919-circa 1936: John Clyde Oswald
  circa 1937-circa 1942: W. Wellington Massee
  circa 1945-circa 1948: J. Walter McSpaden
  circa 1952-?a: Frederick L. Fagley
  circa 1955-circa 1958: Earl B. Breeding
  1958-?a: Robin T. Tait
  Managing Director (later, Manager)
  1899-1903: Charles de Kay
  1932-?: Peter Tivnan
  circa 1956-1959: John Williams
  1959-?: Ara Daglian
  - Board of Governors and Executive Committee, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237)
    - Volume 1, March 1, 1898-April 1905; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237, Frame 6-516)
      (including records of the Organizing Secretary, Charles de Kay, and the Organizing Committee, with copies of the charter, constitution, and house rules)
    - Volume 2, May 1905-Oct. 1908; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237, Frame 517-668)
    - Volume 3, June 1909-June 1910; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237, Frame 669-715)
    - Volume 4 (regarding reorganization), April 12-June 29, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237, Frame 716-745)
    - Volume 5, April 1910-April 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237, Frame 746-893)
    - Volume 6, April 1912-April 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237, Frame 894-979)
    - Volume 7, April 1913-April 1914; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237, Frame 980-1071)
    - Volume 8, April 1914-March 1915; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237, Frame 1072-1219)
    - Volume 9, April 1914-April 1915; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4237, Frame 1220-1235)
    - Volume 9, April 1914-April 1915 cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 8-101)
    - Volume 10, April 1918-April 1919; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 102-244)
    - Volume 11, April 1919-April 1920; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 245-378)
    - Volume 12, April 1920-April 1921; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 379-475)
    - Volume 13, April 1921-April 1922; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 476-596)
    - Volume 14, April 1922-April 1923; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 597-709)
    - Volume 15, April 1923-April 1924; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 710-800)
    - Volume 16, April 1924-April 1925; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 801-904)
    - Volume 17, April 1925-April 1926; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 905-990)
    - Volume 18, April 1926-April 1927; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 991-1095)
    - Volume 19, April 1927-April 1928; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 1096-1177)
    - Miscellaneous loose items, May-Dec. 1928; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 1178-1199)
    - Volume 20, April 1929-April 1930; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 1200-1275)
    - Volume 21, April 1930-April 1931; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 1276-1373)
    - Volume 22, April 1931-April 1932; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4238, Frame 1374-1439)
    - Volume 22, April 1931-April 1932, cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 1-97)
    - Volume 23, April 1932-April 1933; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 98-249)
    - Volume 24, April 1933-April 1934; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 250-354)
    - Volume 25, April 1934-April 1935; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 355-446)
    - Volume 26, April 1935-April 1936; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 447-543)
    - Volume 27, April 1936-April 1937; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 544-617)
    - Volume 28, April 1937-April 1938; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 617-690)
    - Volume 29, April 1938-Dec. 1942; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 691-967)
    - Volume 30, Jan. 1943-Aug. 1943; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 968-986)
    - Disbound volumes and loose minutes, 1943-1960; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4239, Frame 987-1417)
    - Disbound volumes and loose minutes, 1943-1960 cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 6-86)
  - Admissions Committee, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Volume 1, Minutes, April 1901-May 1910; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 90-219)
    - Volume 2, Minutes, June 1910-Dec. 1918; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 220-379)
  - Arts Committee, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Volume 1, Minutes, Oct. 1910-April 1919; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 381-495)
    - Volume 2, Minutes and report, Feb. 1939; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 496-595)
  - Decorative Arts Exhibition Committee, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Minutes, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 596-604)
  - Extension Committee, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Report, 1908; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 605-612)
  - General Committee on Financial Condition, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Report, 1922; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 614-615)
  - House Committee, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Volume 1, Minutes, April 1904-Sept. 1906; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 617-730)
    - Volume 2, Minutes, Aug. 1906-Sept. 1907; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 731-813)
    - Volume 3, Minutes and report, April 1919-July 1921, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 814-921)
  - Committee on Increased Membership, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Report, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 922-924)
  - Committee on Membership, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Consultant's Report, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 925-948)
  - Special Committee of Second Mortgage Bondholders, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Minutes and Reports, 1910, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 949-975)
  - Special Committee on Restaurant, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240)
    - Reports, 1909; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4240, Frame 58-961)
- Administration, 1898-1960, undated; Series 2; Archival Resource Key
  This series contains correspondence of club officers and tends to be routine and administrative, relating particularly to the management of the restaurant and studio building, election of members, and collection of dues. Individual letters concerning important events in the history of the National Arts Club, or relating to art, artists, and the Club's permanent collection are noted in the subseries descriptions.
  This record series is comprised of eight subseries:
  2.1: Officers' Correspondence, 1898-1960, undated
  2.2: President, 1920, 1928
  2.3: Secretary, 1927-1939
  2.4: Treasurer, 1917-1957, undated
  2.5: Manager, 1956-1960
  2.6: House Committee, 1922-1932
  2.7: American Artists War Emergency Fund Committee, 1917-1918
  2.8: Men's Open Table, 1915-1950
  Due to coinciding responsibilities of officers and a number of efforts to organize the records over the years, there is overlap between Officers' Correspondence (especially General Correspondence) and other subseries. Wherever possible and practical, the arrangement reflects what appears to be the filing system used, at some point, by the Club.
  - Officers' Correspondence, 1898-1960, undated; 2.1; Archival Resource Key